var  questions =[{  
    "question":"Let x be an integer which can take a value of 0 or 1. The statement if(x ==0) x = 1; else x = 0; is equivalent to which one of the following?",
    "option1":"x = 1 + x",
    "option2":"x = 1 - x",
    "option3":"x = 1 * x",
    "option4":"x=1 % x",
    "answer":"2",
 },
    {    
    "question":"Assume that objects of the type short, float and long occupy 2 bytes, 4 bytes and 8 bytes, respectively. The memory requirement for variable t  ignoring alignment considerations is ",
    "option1":"22 bytes", 
    "option2":"14 bytes",
    "option3":"18 bytes",
    "option4":"10 bytes",
    "answer":"3",

},{  
    "question":"In C, parameters are always ",
    "option1":"Passed by value", 
    "option2":"Passed by reference",
    "option3":"Passed by value result",
    "option4":"other",
    "answer":"1",

},{  
    "question":"Which of the following is true about return type of functions in C?",
    "option1":"Functions can return any type", 
    "option2":"Functions can return any type except array and functions",
    "option3":"Functions can return any type except array, functions and union",
    "option4":"Functions can return any type except array, functions, function pointer and union",
    "answer":"2",

},{  
    "question":"Which of the following is not a storage class specifier in C?",
    "option1":"static", 
    "option2":"register",
    "option3":"extern",
    "option4":"volatile",
    "answer":"4",
 },{  
    "question":"Which of the following is not a logical operator?",
    "option1":"||", 
    "option2":"|",
    "option3":"&&",
    "option4":"!",
    "answer":"2",

},{  
    "question":"Which file is generated after pre-processing of a C program?",
    "option1":".o", 
    "option2":".p",
    "option3":".i",
    "option4":".m",
    "answer":"3",

},{
    "question":"In C, static storage class cannot be used with",
    "option1":"Global variable",
    "option2":"Local variable",
    "option3":"Funtion parameter",
    "option4":"Function name",
    "answer":"3",

},{
    "question":"Which of the following is true about arrays in C. ",
    "option1":"For every type T, there can be an array of T.",
    "option2":"For every type T except void and function type, there can be an array of T.",
    "option3":"When an array is passed to a function, C compiler creates a copy of array.",
    "option4":"2D arrays are stored in column major form",
    "answer":"2",
},{  
    "question":"Which of the following is true",
    "option1":"gets() doesn't do any array bound testing and should not be used. ", 
    "option2":"fgets() should be used in place of gets() only for files, otherwise gets() is fine",
    "option3":"gets() cannot read strings with spaces",
    "option4":"None of the above",
    "answer":"1",
}];
